Guide to the Sol Stein Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Editorial Consulting, 1950-2004
  - Sub-series II.1: Consulting for Published Materials, 1955-2004
    - Baldwin, James
      - Native Sons, by Sol Stein
        - Draft--with Notes, 2003 March 13 (Box 44, Folder 6)
        - Draft--Rejected Materials, 2003 (Box 44, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 55, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence with Random House, 2003-2004 (Box 55, Folder 2)
        - Manuscript Revisions by Melody R. Guy, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 3)
        - Headnotes, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 4)
        - Reproductions of Baldwin Correspondence--with Design Notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
        - Interior Layouts--with Notes, 2004 January, (2 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 6 to 7)
        - Book Launch Invitations, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 8)
        - Publicity Materials, 2004, (2 Folders) (Box 56, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Press Clippings, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Kazan, Elia
      - The Arrangement
        - Contract with Elia Kazan, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 4)
        - General Editing Notes, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 5)
        - Draft--Incomplete--with Notes, circa 1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 6)
        - Draft--Second, circa 1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Draft--Second--with Notes, circa 1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Draft--Third--with Notes, circa 1960s (Box 35, Folder 3)
        - Draft--Third--with Notes, circa 1960s (Box 36, Folder 1)
        - Draft--Third--with Notes, circa 1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 2 to 3)
        - Draft--Chapter Notes--circa 1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 4 to 7)
        - Draft--Chapter Notes, circa 1960s, (9 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 1 to 9)
        - Correspondence with Elia Kazan, circa 1960s (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - The Assassins
        - Draft--Incomplete--with notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 11)
        - Draft--with Notes, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 12 to 13)
        - Draft--Incomplete--with Notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 14)
        - Draft--with Notes, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
        - Draft--Second--with Notes, undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
        - Draft--Second, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Keyes, Daniel
      - Algernon, Charlie and I --Editorial Suggestions, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II.2: Consulting for Unpublished Materials, undated-1998
    - Basics of Plotting Handout for Workshopsundated (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - The Proximity Organization--by Frank A., Mark A. and Michael D. Armstrong--Draft--with Notes, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Dr. Will--by William Baxter Waddill--Draft, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - California Writing Students--Drafts--with Notes, circa 1990s (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Student Work--Drafts--with Notes, 1993-1996, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Student Work--Dialogue Handout for Workshops, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Socio Economic Suicide, The American Way,-by Kenneth L. Friedman--Draft--with Notes, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Socio Economic Suicide, The American Way, --by Kenneth L. Friedman--Draft--with Notes, circa 1990s, (2 Folders); (including floppy disk of manuscript) (Box 43, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Short Stories--Various Writers--Drafts--with Notes, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - The Malacca Exit--by Jonathan Lynn--Draft--with Notes, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - A Very Civil War--by Michael Shapiro--Draft--with Notes, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series II.3: Beacon Press, 1950-1956
    - Correspondence, 1950-1956, (3 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Mid-Century Essays Correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 51, Folder 15)
- Series III: Organizations, 1951-1962
  - Sub-series III.1: Voice of America, 1951-1953
    - Sub-subseries 1: Transcripts
      - Kevin David Commentaries, circa 1950s (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - “Whose Funeral is Next?”, circa 1950s (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - “Russio-Polish Relations and the Murders in the Katyn Forest”, 1951 April 25 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - “Political Geography”, 1951 September 20 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - “Life Behind the Curtain”, 1952 January 30 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - “ ‘Geronimo’, Cried the Louse”, 1952 February 27 (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - “Totalitarianism”, 1952 December 11 (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - “The Freeing of Slaves”, 1952 December 24 (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - “A New Year’s Message to Communists”, 1952 December 29 (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - “What does America Stand For?, 1953 January 2 (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Where will you Hide?”, 1953 January 19 (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - “The Declaration of Independence”, 1953 January 19 (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - “The Lost Meaning of Freedom”, 1953 January 26 (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - “A Symbol of Unity”, 1953 January 27 (Box 48, Folder 17)
      - “This is our Answer to the Communist Purges”, 1953 January 30 (Box 48, Folder 18)
      - “Five Steps for Evaluating your Society”, 1953 February 4 (Box 48, Folder 19)
      - “Communist Leaders Prefer US Jail to Soviet Freedom”, 1953 February 4 (Box 48, Folder 20)
      - “The Meaning of Brotherhood”, 1953 February 12 (Box 48, Folder 21)
      - “Stalin and the Ten Commandments”, 1953 March 9 (Box 48, Folder 22)
      - “Nobody Envies Georgi Malenkov”, 1953 March 12 (Box 48, Folder 23)
      - “The Bear who Saw Red”, 1953 March 19 (Box 48, Folder 24)
      - “The Trojan Dove”, 1953 April 8 (Box 48, Folder 25)
      - “The World is Waiting”, with Rejection Letter from the Theatre Guild, 1953 April 16 (Box 48, Folder 26)
      - “The Rosenberg Case Nears its Conclusion”, 1953 May 26 (Box 48, Folder 27)
      - “Rumanian-American Refuses to Collaborate with Communism”, 1953 May 27 (Box 48, Folder 28)
      - “Nothing but our Dead”, 1953 May 27 (Box 48, Folder 29)
      - “660 Seconds to Freedom”, 1953 May 28 (Box 48, Folder 30)
      - “Secretary Dulfs Reports on US Near East Relations”, 1953 June 1 (Box 48, Folder 31)
      - “The Ninth Anniversary of D-Day”, 1953 June 5 (Box 48, Folder 32)
      - “Worse than Murder, The Rosenberg’s Crime”, 1953 June 9 (Box 48, Folder 33)
      - “Rosenberg Furore, a Typical Communist Tactic”, 1953 June 11 (Box 48, Folder 34)
      - “Enigma for the Communists: Government by Law”, 1953 June 16 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - “On the Horizon: European Unity”, 1953 June 17 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - “Wasting Human Lives: The Red Offensive in Korea”, 1953 June 18 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - “The Unfinished Story of Willi Gortling”, 1953 June 23 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - “Please do not Visit Our Concentration Camps”, 1953 June 25 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - “The Most Monstrous Crime of All”, 1953 June 26 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - “The Basic Issues of the Cold War”, 1953 July 3 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - “From the Communist Memory-Hole: the Ups and Downs of Thomas Masaryk”, 1953 July 9 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - “First Report from Three-Power Foreign Ministers’ Conference”, 1953 July 11 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - “Second Report from Three-Power Foreign Ministers’ Conference”, 1953 July 11 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - “A Warning to Communists”, 1953 July 14 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - “Please Don’t Leave our Soviet Paradise”, 1953 July 22 (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - “Are there 800,000 Fascists Behind the Iron Curtain?”, 1953 July 23 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - “The Road to Independence and the Road to Slavery”, 1953 July 24 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - “The Human Cost of the Korean War”, 1953 July 31 (Box 49, Folder 15)
      - “Red Youth Jamboree in Rumania”, 1953 August 4 (Box 49, Folder 16)
      - “President Eisenhower Speaks to the Nation”, 1953 August 7 (Box 49, Folder 17)
      - “The Communist Peace Offensive Takes a New Turn”, 1953 August 10 (Box 49, Folder 18)
      - “Why do Communists Torture our Prisoners?”, 1953 August 13 (Box 49, Folder 19)
      - “Mr. Stevenson Returns”, 1953 August 21 (Box 49, Folder 20)
      - “Totalitarian Semantics”, 1953 November 18 (Box 49, Folder 21)
      - “A Rose by any Other Name”, 1953 December 4 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Subject Files, circa 1950s
      - The Death of Stalin, circa 1950s (14) (Box 49, Folder 23)
      - The East German Revolt, circa 1950s (16) (Box 49, Folder 24)
      - The Eclipse of Lawrenti Beria, circa 1950s (17) (Box 49, Folder 25)
      - Germ Warfare, circa 1950s (Box 49, Folder 26)
      - The Nature of Totalitarianism, circa 1950s (Box 49, Folder 27)
      - One Way Traffic: The Great Exodus, circa 1950s (10) (Box 49, Folder 28)
      - The Plot of the Kremlin Doctors, circa 1950s (15) (Box 49, Folder 29)
      - The Rosenberg Case, A Failure of Nerve, circa 1950s (13) (Box 49, Folder 30)
      - Satire as a Weapon, circa 1950s (12) (Box 49, Folder 31)
      - The Soviet Peace Offensive, [undated, 1950s (Box 49, Folder 32)
      - A Specter is Haunting Eastern Europe: Communism, circa 1950s (7) (Box 49, Folder 33)
      - Soviet Art, circa 1950s (Box 49, Folder 34)
      - The Struggle for Succession, circa 1950s (Box 49, Folder 35)
      - US/Soviet Relations, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - USA, the Permanent Revolution, a Brief for Democracy, circa 1950s (11) (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Supplementary Materials, 1951-1953
      - McCarthy, the Great Obfuscator, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Semantics: The War of Words--Draft--Incomplete, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Voice Points to Uprisings--Press Clipping, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Voice of America’s Comments on Communism--Draft, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Broadcast Highlights--1952 December–1953 April (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - New York Herald Tribune--Press Clipping, 1953 January 3 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Policy on Religion, 1951-1953 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Schedule of Programs, 1953 June 17 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Schedule of Programs, 1953 August 7 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Sub-series III.2: American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1952-1958
    - The Congress for Cultural Freedom--Information Booklet, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1993 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - “Is Co-existence Possible?”--Tamiment Institute Forum, 1955 April 4 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - “In Defense of Free Culture”--Conference Promotional Material, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Information Booklet, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Letterheads and Business Card, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Original Invitation to Join, circa 1950s (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Press Release Announcing Sol Stein as Executive Director, 1953 August 28 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Report of Meetings by Sol Stein, 1952 January 4 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Statement Regarding Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1954 March 13 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Tiro, Hasan Muhammad--Correspondence and Press Clippings, 1955-1958 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - “Working for the CIA and Not Knowing It”-- The New York Times--Draft, undated (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Sub-series III.3: New Dramatist’s Committee, 1954-1962
    - Correspondence, 1954-1962 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - Transcript of Craft Discussion with Elia Kazan, 1955 November 7 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Sub-series III.4: Mid-Century Book Society, 1959-1961
    - Contracts, 1959-1961 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1961, (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Minutes, 1961 November 21 (Box 51, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Correspondence, 1943-2002
  - Albee, Edward, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Auchincloss, Louis, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1954-1959 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1980-1990 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Bentley, Eric, 1957-1961 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Buckley, William Jnr., 1955-2002 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Chambers, Whitaker, 1954-1997 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Cheever, John, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Cherne, Leo, 1985-1989 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Criterion Books, 1956-1960 (Box 52, Folder 25)
  - Edelman, Maurice, 1976-1977 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Fiedler, Leslie, 1954-1991 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Fitch, Robert Elliot, 1955-1956 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Frost, David, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Gates, Henry Louis Jnr, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Glazer, Tom, 1972-1980 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Glick, Nathan, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Godwin, Tony, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Greenfeld, George, 1967-1991 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 26)
  - Heath, Edward, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Holman, Nat, 1943-1944 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1954-1985 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Huett, Richard, 1976-1990 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Hurt, William, 1985-1988 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Kazan, Elia, 1952-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 18 to 19)
  - Kazan Family, 1956-1971 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1963 (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Miller, Arthur, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - Morris, Desmond, 1978-1979 (Box 52, Folder 23)
  - Navasky, Victor, 1979-1981 (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - The New York Times, 1980-1991 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Orwell, George, 1954-1955 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Orwell, Sonia, 1955 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Partridge, Eric, 1961-1978 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Schulberg, Budd, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - State University of Iowa, 1957-1961 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Tindall, William York, 1957 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Trilling, Lionel, 1953-1985 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Trilling, Diana, 1955-1975 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Viereck, Peter, 1953 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1954 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Wolf, Bertram, 1953-1957, (3 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 11 to 13)
- Series V: Photographs, 1969-2004, undated
  - Baldwin, James, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Kazan, Elia, undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Stein, Sol, 1969-2004 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Wolfe, Bertram, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 4 to 5)